Melvin Kusters
.NET Engineer / Software Architect
Roserije 241A, 6228 DP Maastricht, Netherlands
+31 (0)6 340 67 905
melvinkusters0@gmail.com

Fluent in Dutch and English

See my LinkedIn profile for more: https://www.linkedin.com/in/melvin-kusters/

Also check out my Portfolio at: melvinkusters.com



Hi, thanks for checking out my profile! I'm a .NET specialist with 5 years of experience in designing and developing enterprise distributed systems with .NET and Angular being my tools of expertise. My most prominent role to date is that of Software Architect at Integraal Kankercentrum Nederland (IKNL), where I was responsible for the greenfield development of a complex system servicing the Dutch national palliative consultation line for 450+ concurrent users. I excel especially in projects where integrating systems and making these integrations maintainable and future-proof is a priority. I am proficient in managing and maintaining deployments and debugging in all stages. My previous employers describe me as a curious and driven team player with a broad knowledge of his work, who loves to get to the bottom of a problem. I have a strong attention to detail and a passion for problem-solving, and I'm always looking for ways to improve my workflow and increase efficiency. One of the most important skills I've learnt over the years is to adapt to any situation and work with whatever tools are best for the job. I work best in an environment where asking questions and sharing knowledge is encouraged; we can always learn from each other and become more efficient on the job once we're unafraid to ask. I'm always open for a chat!

SPECIALIZATIONS

- Designing, developing and deploying enterprise distributed systems in .NET.
- Designing, developing, deploying and taking a leading role in customized VOIP-solutions projects.
- Working closely with stakeholders to refine user requirements and project strategy.
- Bridging non-technical and technical business units as a reliable communicator.
- Managing project strategy, internal resource allocation, timelines, and project realization.

Languages & Frameworks/Libraries: C#, .NET 3.0+, Angular 8+, Typescript, Javascript, LINQ, SQL, MSSQL, HTML, CSS, Git, XUnit, Node.js, Entity Framework Core, RxJS, NgRx, NGXS, SIP, SDP, RTP, gRPC, SignalR, Microsoft Orleans, Rebus, MassTransit (ASB/RabbitMQ).

Practices: CI, CD, TDD (Test-Driven Development), UML, Agile, Scrum, MVC, SOA, DevOps, Containerization, State management, Enterprise Application Integration, Remote Method Invocation (with RPC), Virtual Actor Model, Enterprise Service Bus.

Platforms: Azure (DevOps, Resource management), Docker, GitHub.

 ${\tt Databases:\ MSSQL,\ MongoDB,\ Azure\ Cosmos,\ Azure\ Table\ Storage,\ MySQL.}$

Applications: Kubernetes, Docker, VMWare, VirtualBox Kamailio, RTPEngine, SIPSorcery, OpenSIPS, Asterisk, 3CX (Certified), MikroTik (Certified), RouterOS, SSMS, Visual Studio, VS Code, Wireshark, VoIPMonitor, Oracle EOM, Postman, Rider, Git Extensions, Azure Data Studio, Robo-3T, Azure Storage Explorer, Service Bus Explorer, Fiddler, NSwag.

Environments: Windows-based, GNU/Linux-based.

WORK EXPERIENCE

CTO & Co-founder Dec 2022 – Present

Steep Software B.V. - Eindhoven

Tech stack: .NET Core 7, Angular, Azure

Self-employed as chief technical officer of startup, in charge of:

- Developing (new) SaaS solutions and managing cloud infrastructure, and;
- Advising customers in approaching both technical and social challenges.

Freelance .NET Developer

Apr 2022 - Nov 2022

Quotation Factory B.V. - Eindhoven

Tech stack: .NET 6, Microsoft Orleans, Azure

- Ensured customer success in a critical period for the company by independently delivering customer-facing integrations through systematic communication and the implementation of a rigorous delivery cycle.
- Transformed the existing stack to support international use by implementing variable localization and currency.

Freelance .NET Developer

Oct 2021 - Apr 2022

Selfcare B.V. - Breda

Tech stack: .NET 5, Angular 11, Azure

- Enhanced customer experience by implementing cross-platform chat and overhauling complex interactive features.
- Resolved a major technical bottleneck by initiating and leading a refactoring effort of a core system component.
- Fixed bugs and problems across the entire Selfcare codebase in an efficient, timely manner.

Software Architect Feb 2020 - Apr 2022

Integraal Kankercentrum Nederland - Utrecht

Tech stack: .NET Core 3.1, Angular 12 (Ivy), Azure, SIPSorcery

Centralized staff scheduling and telecommunications for national palliative care services
across 25 regions by designing, developing, deploying and maintaining a complex distributed
system from conception to scale-out resulting in an estimated €2m in yearly budget savings
for the organization.

Portfolio article: A voice for 450+ medical specialists

CTO Mar 2019 – July 2021

IP Central - Zwolle

Tech stack: .NET Core 3.0 > .NET 5, Angular 8 > 12 (Ivy), Azure, MikroTik, BroadWorks

- Enabled partnership with fiber optic network operator by designing and developing an SD-WAN management system capable of automating configuration of an ISP's MikroTik-based network core and CPE management with turn-key settings made available in a web-based partner portal.
- Optimized IP Central's prime customer's call center by designing and developing a
 wallboarding and reporting system supplying on-demand and real-time information on daily
 activity.
- Effectively advised in troubleshooting an ISDN migration for Enexis, securing a €20k monthly deal for routing traffic through IP Central's trunking platform.
- Ensured customer success by becoming the primary point of contact for technical support and handling the day-to-day operations.

Technical Support Engineer

Feb 2016 - Jan 2017

Motto Communications - Nuth

Tech stack: Asterisk, 3CX, Python, PHP

- Reinforced the second-line technical support desk in a time of understaffing and rapid company growth, by quickly transitioning from intern to full employment.
- Wrote and implemented maintenance scripts for Asterisk products, expediting customer support and product delivery.

EDUCATION

Bachelor HBO-ICT | Software Engineering & Cyber Security

2017 - 2020

Fontys Hogescholen Eindhoven

Average score of 10/10 achieved for last three semesters. Specialization in Cyber Security completed.

Niveau 4 MBO-ICT Management

2014 - 2017

ROC Leeuwenborgh

Completed studies and obtained practical experience in customer relations and technical support work through internships.